LEOMAN MOMOH DATA ANALYTICS PROFESSIONAL

☑ Imomoh@icloud.com **901-289-8381** 8900 Research Park Dr. Apt 702 The Woodlands, O Imomoh91/Personal-**Projects**

SKILLS

STATISTICAL ANALYSIS

Hypothesis Tésting Regression Modeling

Hyper Parameter Optimization

A/B Testing

DATA SCIENCE

Data Visualization Machine Learning Algorithms

Data Wrangling Data Cleaning

Advance Excel(Formula, V lookup, Python

LANGUAGES

CODING

SQL **PySpark**

SUMMARY

I am experienced data analytics professional with a background in statistical analysis, data wrangling, and machine learning algorithms. I'm passionate about helping others understand key business opportunities through visualizations and presentations of insight through data. I often attend data science events around Houston to sharpen my skills and learn new techniques within data science.

PROJECTS

METACRITIC PREDICTION MODEL

In this project, I gathered information from the website 'Metacritic' to create a prediction model for future scores. Using python code, I cleaned, manipulated, and visualized the data. After some statistical analysis, I was able to identify the best features for model construction. Ultimately after some optimization, I was able to account for most of the variation between predicted and actual scores. I also wrote a detailed report of my process and recommendations on ways to increase scores.

CONSUMER CLUSTERING PROJECT

In this project, I used consumer data to create an unsupervised clustering model to group consumers based on purchase history. Using python code and data visualization, I manipulated the data to find the optimum number of groups for the model to generate. I found that the model worked best when grouping consumers into 3 distinct groups. Based on those findings, individuals within those 3 groups would each receive unique marketing material based on the groups' purchases history.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

AON HEWITT

Pension Administrator

The Woodlands. Tx 2016 to 2017

- Develop Excel spreadsheets that automatically calculate defined retirement benefits for multiple pension plans using V-lookups, formulas, macros,
- Assist with the creating, testing, and implementing customized calculation system for new clients according to the plan provisions and administrative requirements.
- Create monthly client reports detailing pension plan activity and funds.
- Conduct and test monthly data load to ensure data quality.
- Developed a better data testing process that eliminated errors in our monthly data load procedure by 15% Created and implemented a data mining project to classify and categorize participants within the pension database that were previously missing.
- Developed Mass lump sum solicitations to increase pension lump-sum take rate.

ATHLETICS FEDERATION OF NIGERIA

Professional Athlete Track and Field

Nigeria 2013 to 2016

- World Track and Field championship Qualifier 2013
- 2nd Fastest 800m time in the World 2013
- New balance indoor games champion in 2014

NORTHWESTERN MUTUAL

Financial Planner/ Financial Representative

- 2012 to 2013
- Market financial services to 20-30 different clients weekly, to collaborate on an effective financial plan suiting individual financial goals and needs.
- Develop client reports with visualizations based on financial status and create a presentation to illustrate financial opportunities and needs based on each client's financial goals.
- · Collaborate with managers on ways to market to financial services to multiple demographic groups.

EDUCATION

Springboard

Certification Data Science 2018

University of Arkansas at Fayetteville

B.S.B.A Economics 2014

Favetteville. AR